<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Employees | NIRD Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://nird-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/employees/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nird-blog.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-30T16:14:42-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://nird-blog.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[NIRD, LLC]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet the newest NIRD]]></title>
    <link href="http://nird-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/09/17/meet-the-newest-nird-employee/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T09:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://nird-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/09/17/meet-the-newest-nird-employee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi &ndash; I&rsquo;m Bethany Rentz and I just started working at NIRD on Monday. I&rsquo;m very excited to join the team &ndash; and to start working on client projects! Coming from a large software company &ndash; I&rsquo;m not sure what to expect working at a small office &ndash; but so far everyone is a lot of fun and very enthusiastic. BTW &ndash; we are having an office warming party next week &ndash; which I&rsquo;m sure is also a welcome party for me &ndash; so everyone can check out the new digs: <a href="http://www.meetup.com/NIRD-Seattle/events/136283852/">HQ Warming</a>.</p>

<p>There is a lot of cool stuff going on here &ndash; I got an overview of current projects and what I could work on. There are a couple of projects I will be working on &ndash; and will start getting up to speed on all the NIRD tools.</p>

<p>In the afternoon &ndash; we went out for Frozen Custard &ndash; a NIRD tradition &ndash; and I learned about the company values &ndash; most importantly our focus on the customer and our strong collaboration culture! Then it was time for me to update the NIRD website with my <a href="http://nird.us/bethany">bio</a> &ndash; I made the changes and deployed the code to production.</p>

<p>Over the next couple of weeks I&rsquo;ll be focused on getting up to speed on existing projects and starting to do some development. Hopefully in a future blog post I&rsquo;ll share something more technical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
